<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Text View and Scroll View</string>
    <string name="j_c_bose_university_of_science_and_technology_ymca_faridabad_formerly_ymca_university_of_science_and_technology_was_established_in_2009_by_haryana_state_legislative_act_no_21_of_2009_and_haryana_government_gazette_notification_no_29_of_2009_dated_16_9_2009_before_the_university_came_into_existence_it_had_a_humble_beginning_in_1969_as_ymca_institute_of_engineering_with_an_intake_of_120_students_it_was_an_indo_german_project_a_joint_venture_of_the_state_government_erstwhile_punjab_and_national_council_of_ymcas_of_india_with_active_assistance_from_overseas_agencies_of_west_germany_the_institute_was_started_with_the_aim_to_impart_technical_education_to_a_developing_india_on_german_pattern_and_to_produce_highly_practical_oriented_personnel_in_specialized_fields_of_engineering_to_meet_specific_technical_manpower_requirements_of_industries_during_its_formative_years_the_land_of_20_acres_to_ymcaie_was_provided_by_the_state_government_for_the_construction_of_teaching_block_hostels_and_residential_campus_the_labs_and_workshops_were_set_up_with_the_assistance_of_german_expertise_the_state_govt_started_funding_100_grant_in_aid_to_ymcaie_from_the_year_1994_onwards_and_subsequently_took_over_the_management_and_the_resources_in_the_year_1998_the_ymcaie_was_upgraded_to_the_university_by_the_legislative_act_21_of_2009_the_ugc_granted_the_12_b_status_to_the_university_in_the_year_2012_enabling_it_to_receive_grants_from_ugc_the_university_accredited_by_naac_with_a_grade_in_the_first_circle_of_accreditation_in_the_year_2016_in_2017_it_got_the_status_to_grant_affiliation_to_the_engineering_colleges_situated_in_district_palwal_and_faridabad_in_2018_the_university_was_named_after_the_great_scientist_jagadish_chandra_bose_by_the_state_government_vide_a_notification_dated_11_10_2018_haryana_legislative_act_no_29_of_2018">J.C. Bose University of Science and Technology, YMCA, Faridabad (formerly YMCA University of Science and Technology) was established in 2009 by Haryana State Legislative Act No. 21 of 2009 and Haryana Government Gazette Notification No. 29 of 2009, dated 16.9.2009. Before the University came into existence, it had a humble beginning in 1969 as YMCA Institute of Engineering with an intake of 120 students. It was an Indo-German Project – a Joint Venture of the State Government (erstwhile Punjab) and National Council of YMCAs of India with active assistance from overseas Agencies of West Germany. The Institute was started with the aim to impart technical education to a developing India on German pattern and to produce highly practical oriented personnel in specialized fields of engineering to meet specific technical manpower requirements of industries. During its formative years, the land of 20 acres to YMCAIE was provided by the State Government for the construction of teaching block, hostels and residential campus. The labs and workshops were set up with the assistance of German expertise. The State Govt started funding 100% grant-in-aid to YMCAIE from the year 1994 onwards, and subsequently took over the management and the resources in the year 1998. The YMCAIE was upgraded to the University by the Legislative Act 21 of 2009. The UGC granted the 12(B) status to the University in the Year 2012 enabling it to receive grants from UGC. The University accredited by NAAC with ‘A+’ Grade in the first circle of accreditation in the year 2016. In 2017, it got the status to grant affiliation to the Engineering Colleges situated in district Palwal and Faridabad. In 2018, the University was named after the great scientist Jagadish Chandra Bose by the State Government vide a notification dated 11.10.2018 (Haryana Legislative Act No. 29 of 2018).</string>
</resources>